# Andrew Estornell

### PHD STUDENT · COMPUTER SCIENCE

#### Washington University in Saint Louis

■ aestornell at wustl dot edu | 😭 andrewestornell.github.io

## Research Interests \_\_\_

My research interests fall broadly within the fields of Machine Learning, Algorithmic Fairness, Optimization, Game Theory, and Strategic Classification. I enjoy working on computational problems which involve competitive (or cooperative) behavior between strategic agents, particularly in cases where these agents interact with machine learning systems, e.g. Strategic Classification. Recently my work has focused on Algorithmic Fairness and Strategic Classification, with an emphasis on how these two fields relate to one another.

## Education

## **Washington University in Saint Louis**

PhD in Computer Science

• Advisor: Yevgeniy Vorobeychik

• Advisor: Sanmay Das

**Temple University**BS IN MATHEMATICS

Saint Louis Missouri Aug 2018 - [May-2023]

Philadelphia PA Aug 2015 - May 2018

# Research Experience

#### **Washington University in St Louis - Dept of Computer Science**

St Louis, MO

Advisors: Yevgeniy Vorobeychik, Sanmay Das

Aug 2018 - Present

• PhD dissertation (ongoing): "Consequences and incentives of group-fair learning."

## **Temple University - Dept of Computer Science**

Philadelphia, PA

ADVISOR: KAI ZHANG

Jan 2018- Jun 2018

• Undergraduate research: "Early diagnosis of neurological disorders via patient EEG data."

#### **Temple University - Dept of Mathematics**

Philadelphia, PA

ADVISOR: CHELSEA WALTON

May 2017 - Jun 2018

• Undergraduate research: "Explicit classification of PBW deformations of quadratic monomial algebras."

## Publications \_\_\_\_\_

#### **PUBLISHED**

- [1] Andrew Estornell, Sanmay Das, Brendan Juba, Yevgeniy Vorobeychik. Popularizing Fairness: Group Fairness and Individual Welfare. [To appear] Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI) 2023.
- [2] Junlin Wu, Andrew Estornell, Lecheng Kong, Yevgeniy Vorobeychik. Manipulating Elections by Changing Voter Perceptions. International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI) 2022
- [3] Andrew Estornell, Sanmay Das, Yevgeniy Vorobeychik. Incentivizing Truthfulness Through Audits in Strategic Classification. Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI) 2021.
- [4] Andrew Estornell, Sanmay Das, Edith Elkind, Yevgeniy Vorobeychik. Election Control by Manipulating Issue Significance. Conference on Uncertainty in Artificial Intelligence (UAI) 2020.
- [5] Andrew Estornell, Sanmay Das, Yevgeniy Vorobeychik. Deception Through Half-Truths. Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI) 2020.

[6] Andrew Estornell, Zachary Cline, Chelsea Walton, Matthew Wynne. PBW Deformations of Quadratic Monomial Algebras. Communications in Algebra 2019.

## **UNDER REVIEW**

- [7] Andrew Estornell, Sanmay Das, Yang Liu, Yevgeniy Vorobeychik, 2022. Unfairness Despite Awareness: Group-Fair Classification with Strategic Agents. Appeared at Learning with Strategic Agents Workshop (LSA), and Strategic Machine Learning Workshop (StratML)
- [8] Andrew Estornell, Sanmay Das, Patrick Fowler, Brendan Juba, Pauline Kim, Yevgeniy Vorobeychik 2022. Individual Impacts of Group Fairness in Machine Learning.
- [9] Jinghan Yang, Andrew Estornell, Yevgeniy Vorobeychik, 2022. Location Spoofing Attacks on Autonomous Fleets.

## Awards\_

Best paper (LSA):, "Unfairness Despite Awareness: Group-Fair Classification with Strategic Agents."

### Presentations.

## **CONTRIBUTED PRESENTATIONS AND TALKS**

[To Present] "Popularizing Fairness: Group Fairness and Individual Welfare" at AAAI 2023

Presented "Manipulating Elections by Changing Voter Perceptions" at IJCAI 2022

Presented "Unfairness Despite Awareness: Group-Fair Classification with Strategic Agents" at LSA (AAMAS workshop) 2022, and at StratML (NeurIPS workshop) 2021.

Presented "Incentivizing Truthfulness Through Audits in Strategic Classification" at AAAI, 2021.

Presented "Election Control by Manipulating Issue Significance" at UAI 2020.

Presented "Deception Through Half-Truths" at AAAI 2020.

## Teaching Experience \_\_\_\_\_

Spring 2022

Adversarial AI (CSE.555T), Teaching Assistant

Washington University in Saint Louis

## Professional Development \_\_\_\_\_

## SERVED AS PC/REVIEWER

AAMAS: 2023, 2022

AAAI: 2023, 2022, 2021, 2020 NeurIPS: 2022, 2021, 2020 ICML: 2022

FAccT: 2022 KAIS: 2022 LSA: 2022 AASG: 2021 UAI: 2020

### **PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES**

Languages: Python, Mathematica, C, Java

Libraries: Pytorch, Sklearn, BoTorch, Gym, Tensorflow